<meetingNarrative meeting="data/transcripts/transcript1.txt">
  <person name="Chin" role="supervisor">
    <moment id="1">
      <headline>Workplace Sexual Assault and Harassment Inquiry</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Chin introduces a letter of inquiry to the Department of Human Resources regarding policies and procedures for city employees experiencing sexual assault or harassment in the workplace. She emphasizes San Francisco's long history of supporting survivors, referencing the 2018 creation of the Office of Sexual Harassment and Assault Response and Prevention (SHARP) and the 2022 establishment of the Mayor's Office for Victims Rights. She notes that sexual assault and harassment are deeply pervasive, impact multiple generations, and are often invisible and underreported. She seeks to understand current protocols and ensure culturally competent best practices are in place.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:21:48, 00:22:00, 00:22:15, 00:22:38, 00:23:02, 00:23:07, 00:23:22</timestamps>
    </moment>
  </person>
  <person name="Dorsey" role="supervisor">
    <moment id="1">
      <headline>Surveillance Technology Compliance Burden Investigation</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Dorsey notifies heads of 41 city departments of his intent to submit letters of inquiry requesting estimates of time and staff resources devoted to complying with the 2019 Surveillance Technology Ordinance (Admin Code Chapter 19B). He describes the ordinance as "labyrinthine," noting its 12,500-word, 22-page structure that imposes significant research, reporting, oversight, and engagement burdens on city agencies. The ordinance requires departments to submit surveillance technology inventories, impact reports, policies, and annual (now biannual) surveillance reports through a complex approval process involving the Privacy Surveillance Advisory Board and Board of Supervisors. Dorsey previously proposed removing the ordinance's prevailing plaintiffs' fees provision, but now seeks to quantify the larger investment of taxpayer-funded resources for compliance. He emphasizes this inquiry is timely given ongoing efforts to improve government efficiencies and cut waste, and notes the ordinance has important implications for public safety and effective policing.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:23:27, 00:23:32, 00:23:45, 00:24:00, 00:24:17, 00:24:49, 00:25:04, 00:25:27, 00:26:01, 00:26:18, 00:26:34</timestamps>
    </moment>
    <moment id="2">
      <headline>Celebrating 104-Year-Old Community Servant Maria Tan</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Dorsey honors Maria Tan, a 104-year-old immigrant who embodies the strength and resilience that has shaped San Francisco. Born September 25, 1921, in the Philippines to Chinese immigrant parents, Maria came to the United States in 1978 and became an American citizen. She has been a San Francisco resident since 1982. For more than three decades, Maria devoted herself to service through Self-Help for the Elderly and later as a volunteer at Old Saint Mary's Bookstore, touching countless lives with quiet and steady kindness. A devoted parishioner at Old Saint Mary's Cathedral, she has drawn strength from her Catholic faith and forged enduring friendships. She finds peace in Muir Woods and shares her love of poetry through reading and writing. As a devoted mother of four, she has passed down values of love, perseverance, and faith. Her daughter Carol accepts the commendation, sharing that Maria remains feisty, happy, and vibrant at 104, asking caregivers to dance with her as her primary form of communication. Carol credits her mother's example of civic duty, noting she now works for the School District serving special needs students.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:45:57, 00:46:04, 00:46:19, 00:46:31, 00:46:56, 00:47:00, 00:47:31, 00:48:01, 00:48:25, 00:49:00, 00:49:19, 00:50:00, 00:50:38, 00:51:01</timestamps>
    </moment>
  </person>
  <person name="Mahmood" role="supervisor">
    <moment id="1">
      <headline>Honoring Veteran and Community Advocate Douglas Jenkins</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Mahmood honors Douglas Jenkins, a proud veteran and lifelong advocate whose service has strengthened the Fillmore and neighborhoods across the city for over 40 years. Jenkins began his military career in the U.S. Army in North Carolina before relocating to the Bay Area in the 1980s, continuing his service for over two decades in the Army Reserves at the Presidio, achieving the rank of Staff Sergeant. During the 1980s and 1990s, he stood up against urban renewal and Western Addition displacement, fighting on behalf of the Black community. Jenkins is a proud member of New Liberation Presbyterian Church, mentors younger generations, volunteers as a poll worker, and serves as a connector and source of joy at the Booker T Washington Community Service Center. He is also a small business owner who ran Bright Image Cosmetic Center in the Bayview for 36 years. Friends describe him as a kind, gentle soul who is energetic, happy, and a straight shooter who speaks his mind when needed. The commendation celebrates Jenkins as the embodiment of service—both in uniform and in action.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:41:30, 00:41:40, 00:42:01, 00:42:12, 00:42:32, 00:42:43, 00:42:48, 00:43:13, 00:43:29, 00:43:51, 00:44:06</timestamps>
    </moment>
  </person>
  <person name="Sauter" role="supervisor">
    <moment id="1">
      <headline>District 3 Neighborhood Cleanup Volunteers Recognition</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Sauter honors the dedicated volunteers who lead District 3's neighborhood cleanups every weekend. She describes their commitment: they don orange vests, grab pickers and brooms, and systematically collect thousands of bags of trash from streets across Chinatown, North Beach, Russian Hill, and Polk Street. The cleanup captains—including Jessica Lee (Chinatown), Dallas Hyatt (Lower Hill), Eric Bauer and Debbie Markey (North Beach), and Laura Palin (Upper Polk)—are unpaid volunteers who sacrifice Saturday and Sunday mornings, often storing equipment in their own garages. Sauter emphasizes that while these cleanups address symptoms of waste, the board must tackle upstream causes, particularly cigarette litter. She calls for San Francisco to follow the lead of Santa Cruz County, Capitola, Tiburon, and Baltimore in banning filtered tobacco products. She also credits support systems including Vince You (Refuse Refuse), Caleb (Civic Joy Fund), and DPW workers. The commendation celebrates community-building and the transformation of neighborhoods through collective action.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:33:40, 00:33:49, 00:34:08, 00:34:18, 00:35:12, 00:35:38, 00:36:00, 00:36:29, 00:37:08, 00:38:35, 00:39:06, 00:39:21, 00:40:06</timestamps>
    </moment>
  </person>
  <person name="Cheryl" role="supervisor">
    <moment id="1">
      <headline>Honoring 107-Year-Old Community Elder</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Cheryl commends Cho Chang Yao on her 107th birthday, celebrating her as one of the oldest living San Franciscans. She highlights Yao's remarkable life: born in Honolulu in 1918, she was crowned one of four beauty queens in Zhongshan City, Guangdong at a young age. At 20, she married Dr. Cho Long Chung, director of Canton Hospital, and together they built a life in Macao raising seven children. She now has 16 grandchildren and 19 great-grandchildren. Supervisor Cheryl emphasizes Yao's legacy of family, strength, perseverance, and resilience. She also highlights the work of Yao's granddaughter Leslie Hieu, who founded Pierce's Pledge in honor of her late son to prevent family violence and promote firearms safety reforms. The commendation celebrates Yao's century-long life of purpose, love, and family across generations.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:27:00, 00:27:05, 00:27:16, 00:27:36, 00:28:02, 00:28:22, 00:28:44, 00:29:02, 00:29:19, 00:29:39, 00:30:01</timestamps>
    </moment>
  </person>
  <person name="Walton" role="supervisor">
    <moment id="1">
      <headline>Honoring Il Pirata and Billy Cortese: A Neighborhood Institution</headline>
      <summary>
        <\![CDATA[
        Supervisor Walton honors Billy Cortese and the beloved neighborhood institution Il Pirata, which has stood as a gathering place for neighbors, artists, and families for generations. Il Pirata embodies the warmth, diversity, and creative spirit that makes San Francisco special. What began as a family endeavor has grown into a neighborhood landmark passed down through generations of ownership devoted to community, hospitality, and heart. When Billy's family took over Il Pirata in 1994, Petro Hill was a different place, but through every wave of change—tech booms, building cranes, and rising rents—they kept Il Pirata grounded. They ensured there was always a place for working people, musicians, dreamers, and anyone needing a good meal, good music, and a familiar face behind the bar. From legendary salsa nights to its role as a gathering place for locals and visitors, Il Pirata has been a cornerstone of Petro Hill where community, culture, and connection thrive. The commendation celebrates the family's commitment to maintaining this living legacy in a city that continues to evolve.
        ]]>
      </summary>
      <timestamps>00:52:10, 00:52:25, 00:52:32, 00:52:45, 00:53:00, 00:53:14, 00:53:30, 00:53:42, 00:54:00, 00:54:06</timestamps>
    </moment>
  </person>
</meetingNarrative>
